VAIBHAV SONI

+918302665842

vssonivaibhav6@gmail.com vaibhavsoni.com

OBJECTIVE

I am a software professional with more than 6 years of professional experience in designing, developing and delivering software applications and products. I have worked on a range of technologies from C++ application development to Javascript based web applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Oct 2020 - present (Remote)

Alepo

Alepo makes next-generation data opportunities a reality, creating advanced software solutions and services that enable global communications service providers to accelerate revenue growth, market share, and business success on fixed and mobile broadband networks.

R&D 5g team - Role: Technical Architect

- ✓ Responsible for evaluating and benchmarking and creating POC's of different technologies which could be a possible fit in current ecosystem or provide better performance. Some of the technologies evaluated are Kafka, sonarqube, sso engines, confluence plugins, document generating tools like swagger etc.
- ✓ Wrote a matching engine in Lua
- ✓ Developed an Fault manager and KPI collector microservices which acts like a bridge between different alerting system like Prometheus and existing microservices
- ✓ Co-Architected Licensing server for 5g Products
- ✓ Architected and developed Configuration manager using nodejs and ETCD
- ✓ Worked on 5g PCF (Policy Function Control) development
- ✓ Interacted with clients for integrating our products with their systems

Xooa empowers users of all blockchain expertise levels to build NFT marketplaces and other blockchain apps on the cloud fast through a streamlined and easy-to-use interface. Take advantage of Xooa's low code tools, API gateway, and many other powerful features to generate up to a 10x faster time-to-app and a 95% shorter learning curve.

Role: Team lead

- Responsible for hiring for dev roles and providing them a seamless onboarding with current codebase
- ✓ Helped teams clearing technical backlogs, and made product more stable
- Connecting with clients to resolve their product related queries and gather future development requirements
- Creating technical requirements for features and managing sprints
- ✓ Distributing Jira tickets and helping team with day to day operations
- Developed self-serve capabilities which allowed users to configure and operated various aspects of product seamlessly
- ✓ Developed various products plugins like Wailtlist , Customisable carousels etc
- Responsible for code quality and PR reviews

Xtreme Blockchain Labs created a Cryptocurrency exchange which helps users to trade cryptocurrencies like BTC , ETH , LTC etc for Canadian nationalists.

- Build a custom logger node module to create logs in defined format and to be pushed to Elasticsearch.
- ✓ Build A tracking system to track communication between microservices. includes developing 2 node modules to track Rest calls and one to track messages from redis kue.
- ✓ Enhanced Testing by writing test cases in MochaJs, ChaiJs
- ✓ Created Kibana Dashboards for the tracking systems;
- Created microservice to fanout data from Trade Data aggregators to different sockets to plot Candlestick charts and manage historical data with influx db(time series database).
- ✓ Created a streaming microservice framework for node & kafka stream
- Created Ethereum based smart contracts in solidity for some pocs.
- Created Artillery scripts to load test and benchmark for trades in trade engine.
- ✓ Helped team by actively reviewing code and creating curd based features for various use cases across the other microservices like trading engine, kyc, wallted management etc.

Feb 2017 - Oct 2018

Apiria (Now acquired by jupiter.money)

Apiria is virtual assistant for modern age employees. A significant amount of productive time is spent by an employee on performing mundane and repetitive activity on a HR portal. Apiria is that 'smart' system which not only shows relevant information but also performs automated tasks to increase employee productivity.

- ✓ Build a workflow Application from scratch using Reactjs , Nodejs , Graphql , Mongodb.
- ✓ Worked on developing api-servers for supporting application's frontend using rest api's and graphql.
- ✓ Wrote Payroll Engine which was able to calculate taxes as per Indian laws
- Enhanced Testing by writing test cases in MochaJs and automating tasks using Grunt
- Designed and developed features which would help user to setup the application in various modes
- ✓ Designed and developed various features like Expense Management System for the application
- Developed Frontend in Angularis for the various feature of the application

Aug 2016 – Feb 2017

Cantern

Cantern is an educational analytics company, they enable colleges to enhance their profile and students' employability through the power of data, aggregate the data from various sources and employ a series of algorithms to understand and convert the raw data to useful insights for the college.

- ✓ Worked on developing product from scratch which includes Dashboard and different servers
- ✓ Worked On developing Reporting framework which include usages of Phantom Js , Nodejs ,MongoDb ,Expressjs
- ✓ Have Also worked on Charting and graph libraries like Morris js , Plottable js , C3js etc .
- Developed various in house tools to make download and modify reports

Eronkan provides various IIOT services to enterprises. I have worked on the core product features and also internal tools. The technology stack that I was involved in consisted of Node JS and EmberJS.

- ✓ Responsible for maintaining beta version of the product on an ec2 instances which include updating source code, regularly test new features etc.
- ✓ Worked on building a monitoring system which keep check on driver's status installed on client's system.
- ✓ Worked on automation of server related task using monit, upstart and shell scripts.
- ✓ Worked on various customizations of frontend templates to fulfil client requirements.
- ✓ Worked on developing various api used for various features in the framework, developed using various tools like redis, rabbitmq, sqs etc.
- ✓ Worked on developing alerting systems which uses sms, mails to send alert to customers in case of various client defined situations.
- ✓ Have also made many clients visit where I was responsible to fetch data from FANUC CNC machine using RS232 ports.

SKILLS

JavaScript, Nodejs, AngularJs, Angular8+, Ionic 4, Reactjs, Mochajs, Graphql, HTML, CSS, Team management, Project management, PostgreSQL, Cassandra, Redis, Rabbitmq, Linux, AWS SQS, Kafka, Monit, git, ACE editor, Bootstrap, Processing, Knexjs, Server-Administration etc.

OTHER COURSES

- ✓ Introduction to Computational Arts (University Of New York Online).
- ✓ HTML5.1x: Web Design Fundamentals (Part 1) (Through edx.org by W3C)

INTERNSHIP

Girnar Technologies Pvt ltd Jaipur

WORKSHOPS & SEMINARS

- ✓ Ethical Hacking 1.0 & lab by i3indya Technologies at Neuron 12 MNIT Jaipur on 4th Nov 2012.
- ✓ NEN Entrepreneur Workshop Held at college campus.
- ✓ Attended Infosys Campus Connect workshops held at college

EDUCATION

2015	Bachelor of Technology (RTU) (Computer Science) Poornima Institute Of Engineering And Technology Jaipur, Rajasthan, India
2010	Higher Secondary Certificate (12 th) (CBSE),Army Public School, Bikaner, Rajasthan, India
2008	Secondary School Certificate(10 th) (CBSE),Army Public School, Bikaner, Rajasthan, India